

hilaryrallo.com

## Professional Summary

Front-End Web developer with 4 years experience planning and developing client sites. Applicable web development experience includes: communicating and leading internal team to ensure successful development, quality assurance, and delivery of site to client. Strong experience with HTML5, CSS3, grid frameworks, and responsive experiences. Experience assuring bug-free and industry standards for best SEO practices. Worked with design team to ensure efficient structure for development infrastructure. Implemented proper use of tools, naming conventions, and other various best practices. Continuously researching best web principles and usability to ensure best user experience. High skills of communication and collaboration as well as ambition to sharpen existing skills and grow lacking skills. Helped to implement agile process and was a scrum master for a development team consisting of 5 people.

# Technical Summary

Tools	Web Development	Key Skills
Mac OS X Adobe Suite Sketch Codekit Terminal MAMP Chrome Firefox Internet Explorer Safari FileZilla xcode Sublime Text	CSS3 - Advanced LESS - Advanced SASS - Advanced HTML5 - Advanced Javascript - Intermediate PHP - Intermediate Actionscript 3.0 - Beginner Git - Intermediate  Frameworks  Material Design - Advanced Bourbon - Advanced Bourbon Neat - Advanced AngularJS - Intermediate jQuery - Intermediate	Responsive Sites Wireframing/Mockups Requirement Gathering User Experience Collaboration QA/Testing Implementation/Go-Live Maintenance/Support Troubleshooting Agile Scrum Mastering

### Education

Webster University, St. Louis, MO BA In Interactive Digital Media

# Professional Experience

Integrity, St. Louis, MO Front-end Developer & Scrum Master 5/2012 - 8/2013

Integrity is a leader in the St. Louis web marketing scene, helping companies with anything from growing SEO hits to building complex web applications. While there, I was part of a web development team responsible for creating marketing sites, most often through the Wordpress.org CMS. Starting in January I was also responsible for leading a development team as the scrum master using agile.

Key ac	:hievements:
	Lead team using Agile development process
	Collaborate with design, project managers, and back-end development
	Converted psds into functional websites using wordpress cms with custom built theme and plugins
	Hand-coded HTML5 and CSS3 using bootstrap framework built on dynamic LESS CSS
	Implement and extend various jQuery plugins such as accordions and responsive menus
	Utilized best-practices in HTML5 structures and CSS3 styling to ensure bug-free quality code
	Used Git version control system to ensure code was collaborative and of the highest quality before launch
	Support and maintenance on around 15 different various sites

Rose Design, St. Louis, MO Front-end Developer 8/2013 - 2/2014

Rose Design is a small company helping clients with custom print and web solutions.

<ul> <li>Key Achievements:</li> <li>Help teach the current developer newer technologies such as develor responsive and a css preprocessor.</li> <li>Help redesign and develop their existing internal site to give them as cutting edge look and feel</li> <li>Use svn to track code</li> <li>Support and maintenance on several sites</li> </ul>	
Singularity Interactive, Boulder, CO Front-end Developer 2/2014 - Current	
Singularity Interactive is a start-up that currently does consulting work with be an immersive gaming company. My time is spent helping to build a large app, polymer.gloo.us.	-
<ul> <li>Key Achievements:</li> <li>Prototype and build UI for custom app</li> <li>Build and upkeep a custom responsive css framework</li> <li>Help bridge the gap between development and design teams</li> <li>Used Git version control system to ensure code was collaborative an highest quality before launch</li> <li>Used Angularjs to contribute to app and consume APIs</li> </ul>	nd of the